software4students.co.uk 2018-10-12

# Privacy Policy - Software4Students

Software4Students is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. Although we will do our utmost to protect your information, we cannot guarantee the security of the data you submit to our website or our app; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures to try to prevent unauthorised access.

We will never pass on information about you unless we are legally obliged to do so. We will never use any of your data in ways that have unjustified adverse effects on you.

Software4Students contains links to third party stores and websites. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies. You should take reasonable steps to check their policies before you submit any personal data to their websites.

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will do our best and take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

The information you give us can be used as shown below;

## Your name and contact information

Software4Students only holds and uses personal information, such as your name, email address and delivery address to provide service to our members.

These services include, but are not restricted to; making delivery easier by holding default details for delivery, issuing reminders and gift suggestions for birthdays and other occasions, and tailoring bargain notices and other portal content to member’s individual preferences. To this end, information collected on members will only be made available to portal retailers and the portal itself and will not be disclosed to any third party without prior consent being obtained from the member or members concerned. We may also use your information to contact you regarding an order you place. 

We will never pass on your email address to third parties.

When you email us, use our live chat service or phone us, we retain details of our communications. We may use this data to provide you with service and support. We may also use this data to train our staff.

When you add items to your cart, our website remembers what you added. If you remove an item, we will no longer keep that record. We may send you an email to remind you that you have items in your cart. You can set your preference about receiving these emails in your account settings through this link

We store your purchase history in order to provide customer service, and handle returns.

We may use your purchase history to send you a personal email about consumable products you have bought from us in the past, as a reminder that you may need to order some replacements. You can set your preference about receiving these emails in your account settings through this link

When you browse our website, information is sent to us which includes your IP address, what pages you have visited, your device type and internet browser details. Your IP address may give us information about your location. This data is used for analytical information to help us improve our website, and so we can monitor our service levels. The information we store can also be used to help prevent fraud.

We do not, and will not, sell any of your personal data to any third party. We respect your privacy and protecting your privacy is an important part of the service we provide.

However, as an essential part of the service we provide, we share your data with the following categories of companies:

Companies that do things to get your purchases to you, including payment service providers (to provide payment for your order), warehouses (to pack and dispatch your order), and delivery companies.

Companies who provide a service to collect reviews about our service and products. You may be contacted directly by an independent review company, who will ask you to review your order. 

We may provide third parties with aggregated but anonymised information and analytics about our customers, and we will ensure that it is not possible not identify you from this type of data sharing.

On subscribing to our mailing list, we will send you information by email about products, and special offers that are available.

On subscribing to our mailing list we will also send you an email to remind you that you have items in your shopping cart.

How to stop marketing message’s

To stop marketing messages;

  * You can click the unsubscribe link on any marketing message.
  * Alternatively, you can contact us and request to be removed.

Removal from the mailing list is usually instant, however if an email is scheduled to be sent you might receive one more while your request is being processed.

If you unsubscribe from our mailing list, messages about your orders (such as confirmation emails) and other essential service communications will continue.

Like many companies, we may target banners and adverts to you when you are on other websites and apps. We do this using a variety of digital marketing networks and ad exchanges, and we use a range of advertising technologies like web beacons, pixels, ad tags, cookies, and mobile identifiers, as well as specific services offered by some sites and social networks.

The banners and ads you see may be based on information we hold about you, or your previous use of Software4Students.

You have the following rights relating to your personal information;

  * The right to be informed about how your personal information is being used (this page)
  * The right to access the personal information we hold about you
  * The right to request the correction of inaccurate personal information we hold about you. You can do this by contact our customer support team at [support@software4students.co.uk](mailto:support@software4students.co.uk)
  * The right to request that we delete your data, or stop processing it or collecting it, in some circumstances.
  * The right to stop direct marketing messages, which you can do this by contact our customer support team at support@software4students.co.uk and to withdraw consent for other consent-based processing at any time.
  * The right to request that we transfer or port elements of your data either to you or another service provider.
  * The right to complain to your data protection regulator.

If you want to exercise your rights, have a complaint, or just have questions, please [contact us](http://www.software4students.co.uk/contact-us).

We may change this page from time to time, to reflect how we are processing your data. Please check this page for updates. If we make changes the date of the change will be updated at the bottom of this page.

If we make significant changes, we will make that clear on our website, or by some other means of contact such as email, so that you are able to review the changes before you continue to use our site.

We will not change the way we use your data without informing you and where required, requesting your consent to do so.

Our Service uses "cookies" to distinguish you from other users of our Service and to anonymously track visiting and browsing patterns. 

Cookies are used by most website operators to support website functionality. A cookie is a small text file implanted on the hard disk of your computer when you visit the site. Cookies can contain information about the user, such as your name, address, e-mail details and your user preferences. 

While cookies and the information they obtain may not identify a living individual on their own, they may be able to do so in combination with other information held by us or a third party. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our Service and also allows us to improve our site. 

The cookies used on our website have been categorised based on the guidelines found in the ICC UK Cookie guide as follows:

## Strictly Necessary Cookies

These cookies are essential to enable you to browse around our website and use its features. Without these cookies, services like shopping baskets and online payments cannot be provided.

## Performance Cookies

These cookies collect information about how you use our website — for instance, which pages you go to the most. This data may be used to help optimise our website and make it easier for you to navigate. These cookies are also used to let affiliates know if you go to their website via an affiliate link and if your visit resulted in the purchase of a product with them, including details of the product you purchased. These cookies don’t collect information that identifies you. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous.

## Functionality Cookies

These cookies allow our website to remember choices you make while browsing.

## Our use of cookies and similar technologies 

### Sign-in and authentication: 

When you sign into your Software4Students account using your account details, we store a unique ID and the time you signed in within an encrypted cookie on your device. This cookie allows you to move from page to page within the site without having to sign in again on each page. 

### Third party advertisers: 

Some external product links will forward to third part advertisers from where the product is made available for you to purchase. Such links are provided through affiliate programs that Software4Students provide on the website.

### Analytics: 

In order to provide our products, we use cookies and other identifiers to gather usage and performance data. For example, we use cookies to count the number of unique visitors to a web page or service and to develop other statistics about the operations of our products. This includes cookies from GoConqr and from third-party analytics providers, such as Google Analytics, Alexa and New Relic. 

We prohibit analytics providers from collecting or accessing information that directly identifies you (such as your name or email address). You can opt out of data collection from Google Analytics here: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> (requires you to install a browser add-on) 

Analytics and performance data collected through cookies is always anonymous and aggregated. 

By using Google's Analytics service (used by millions of websites), this provides us with statistics to our website and requires some of the Google cookies which do not store any personal data. The cookies are as follows:-

__utma - expires after 2 years

__utmb - expires after 30 minutes

__utmc - expires when your browser session ends

__utmz - expires after 6 months

## How to control cookies 

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but provide controls that allow you to block or delete them. Details on how to block or delete cookies will vary depending on the browser being used, but instructions should be available in each browser's privacy or help documentation. 

Certain features of the Software4Students service depend on cookies. Please be aware that if you choose to block cookies, you may not be able to sign in or use many features of the Software4Students platform and any preferences that are dependent on cookies may be lost. If you choose to delete cookies, settings and preferences controlled by those cookies, including advertising preferences, will be deleted and may need to be recreated. 

Persons under the age of eighteen (18) should not transfer any Personal Information to us. We will neither intentionally ask for Personal Information of persons under the age of eighteen, nor process their Personal Information.

We do not intentionally collect or maintain information from visitors of the Site or Store who are under thirteen (13) years old.

Information shall be retained by Software4Students for the duration of an individual's membership. Membership is for an indefinite period but may be terminated at the member’s request (by following your rights as stated in this privacy policy) or by Software4Students for any breach of our [terms and condition](http://www.software4students.co.uk/terms).

If you have any questions about this notice or want to exercise any of your rights as set out above, please contact us through our [contact form](http://www.software4students.co.uk/contact-us).
